CONTACT

Address:

24, Adenola Street, Tipper, Ketu, Lagos State, Nigeria.

Phone No:

+2348101667695

Email Address:

josephuguru@gmail.com

Social Media:

twitter.com/josephuguru linkedin.com/in/joseph-uguru-okorie

PORTFOLIO



josephuguru.netlify.app/



github.com/joshboy16



dribbble.com/jojoson



behance.net/josephjohnathan

SKILLS

Javascript(ReactJS/NextJS/NodeJS)

Python

O.S.(Linux/Windows)

Bash Scripting

Basic Networking

Typescript

Docker/Kubernates

Database Management

Nginx/Apache2

Jira (Kanban and Scrum)

Git/GitHub

MySQL/MongoDB/PostgreSQL

RestAPI/GraphQL

AWS

Figma

Terraform/Ansible

Jenkins

Wordpress (PHP)

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

IGBO

YORUBA

HAUSA

FRENCH

JOSEPH JONATHAN UGURU-OKORIE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

Resourceful Software Engineer with over 3 years of in-depth experience in designing, developing, deploying and managing of software applications, and effectively handling configurations of infrastructures and services. Also gained hands-on experience in using python and Javascript in developing web aplications, and also extensive use of AWS services and resources.

EXPERIENCES

JOJOSONS BUSINESS ESTSBLISHMENTS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - 2022-PRESENT

- Utilized MySQL and MongoDB deliverables on the backend component while maintaining necessary technical knowledge and skills.
- Scrapped the web and created data pipelines using python/pandas, excel and pysimpleGUI tools.

Experience in using and building components in ReactJS using Typescript, HTMI,

- CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind etc.
- Have developed full-stack applications using ReactJS and NodeJS web development tools with authentication and authorisation features.
- Designed, developed and interacted with RESTful APIs to maintain operations continuity and productivity.
- Have extensive experience with version control system (Git/GitHub).
- Experience with CI tools (Jenkins) and Build tools (Pip and Virtualenv).
- Designed and tested complex APIs for integration with frontend libraries.

MARTINEZ KNIGHT TECH DESIGNS

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER - 2020 - 2022

- Performed coding and debugging of tasks in support of a project.
- Ensured the performance, quality, and responsiveness of applications.
- Planned, wrote, debugged web applications with high accuracy.
- Developed landing pages and online applications using Reactis.
- Developed scalable web-based APIs (RESTAPI & GraphQL) using Django Rest Framework and Nodejs, respectively.
- Developed a news web app using nodejs at the backend and reactjs for the frontend.

EDUCATION

- Ekiti State University, Ekiti State. (2012-2018).
- Christ's School, Ado-Ekiti, Ekiti State. (2005-2011).
- Ezechi Primary School, Bende, Abia State. (2002-2005).
- UNAD Staff School, Ado-Ekiti, Ekiti State. (1999-2002).

CERTIFICATIONS

- Website Development and Design (2019).
- B.Sc in Psychology: Second Class Honors Upper Division (2018).